

Toronto, M4G 0A5 🏫

(647) 799 - 5944



dikshabhatnagarofficial@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/dikshabhatnagar/ in

Product Designer with a strong background in technical support & product management; Focused on analyzing complex data to make logical deductions while ensuring beautiful, user-centered, and usable products are delivered within the given deadline.

## Skills

Design Skills: Requirement gathering, Market research, Competitive analysis, User research, Persona creation, Task analysis, User flow mapping, Storyboarding, Information Architecture (including Sitemaps), Wireframing & Prototyping, Usability testing, Multi-variate & A/B testing, Human-centered design, Material design, WCAG 2.0.

Technical Skills: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Agile (Scrum), Waterfall, Project Management (PRINCE2), Google Analytics, CMS Design, Mobile Design (Material & iOS), Web Design, UAT & Beta testing, Forecasting & KPI management.

Tools Used: Figma, Adobe XD, InVision, UsabilityHub, OptimalSorting, Miro, Notion, SurveyMonkey, Webflow, Jira & Confluence, Git, Visual Studio, Salesforce, Azure & Trello.

# **Extra Projects**

**PAYWAVE** 

## FinTech App (View Portfolio)

2022-2023, Toronto, CA

Problem: How can we help our users (using AI) foster strong financial habits and store/transfer their wealth while eliminating the need to carry multiple physical cards.

Design Process Phases: Market Research, User Survey & Interviews, Persona Development, Task Analysis & User Flow, Information Architecture (including Sitemaps), Wireframing, Usability Testing & Prototyping.

**Solution**: Designed an app following the double-diamond design process from where the users can not only add and manage multiple cards from one place, but can also setup an automatic savings plan.

# **Experience**

IT SERVICE DESK MANAGER

### Pillar To Post

2021- Present, Toronto, CA

Designed a new mobile application from the start to finish, aimed at helping inspectors in examining cramped and hazardous spaces such as attics and roofs. The application achieved our highest adoption rate with 82% of the users starting to use it in the first week itself.

Analyzed the findings from our user research and feedback session, to redesign our iPad(iOS)
based application. Though the project is planned to go live in late June, it has already gathered
some great feedback from our Pilot group and other internal teams.

### TEAM LEAD, TECHNICAL SUPPORT

### Seagate Technology

2018 - 2021, Toronto, CA

- Managed a team of 10 technical members in one of Seagate's most expensive line of products (Data recovery).
- Created a process to automatically email the clients when their data recovery devices reach a new milestone, to keep the user's engaged and informed. This led to a significant increase in the client base by approximately 27%.

#### PRODUCT MANAGER

#### Koovs.com

2014 - 2018, Toronto, CA

- Led to a significant increase of 31% in our website traffic by designing a platform from where both our social marketing & visual merchandizing teams were able to create a curated look.
- Handled the concept to launch of a visual merchandizing tool that helped optimize product visibility on a page using algorithms like inventory count, color, etc. leading to an increase of 27% in inventory turnover ratio.
- Spearheaded numerous direct mail marketing campaigns; supervised A/B spilt testing for lead generation emails resulting in an open rate increase of 11% and CTR increase of 22%.

# **Education**

Certificate in User Experience Design | CareerFoundry | Toronto, CA

Post Graduate Diploma in Business Administration | University of Otago | Dunedin, NZ